<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tri Tran</title>
    <link>https://nickelium.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Tri Tran</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 21:16:07 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nickelium.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>IRadiance - RayTracer</title>
      <link>https://nickelium.github.io/portfolio/raytracer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 21:16:07 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nickelium.github.io/portfolio/raytracer/</guid>
      <description>IRadiance Engine is an open-source software raytraced renderer written in C++11. This project is still in development, more features are about to come!
Previously I&amp;rsquo;ve written a raytracer based on the implementation of Ray Tracing in One Weekend, from Peter Shirley and Paul Heckbert&amp;rsquo;s business card raytracer. What I did back then was writing the output to a simple image format, .PPM, which requires a specialized software to view the image.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radiance - Graphics Engine</title>
      <link>https://nickelium.github.io/portfolio/graphics_engine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 21:16:07 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nickelium.github.io/portfolio/graphics_engine/</guid>
      <description>Radiance Engine is a graphics engine built currently on top of OpenGL but with the intent to eventually support more APIs. This project is still in development, more features are about to come!
Initially this project was mostly intended as a practical exercise to reinforce the things I&amp;rsquo;ve learned on LearnOpenGL. The goal has evolved into an API agnostic renderer with a clear software architecture. Next up is providing a simple but nice API to the user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://nickelium.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 12:58:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nickelium.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>.image{ margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 10px; margin-top: 0px; margin-bottom:1px; max-width: 40%; width: auto\90.3; / ie8 */ height: auto; float: left; border: 3px solid #bdc2c9; }  Hi! I&amp;rsquo;m Tri Tran an upcoming college graduate from Howest, Belgium, right now living in Brussels, Belgium. Currently I&amp;rsquo;m looking for an internship for the period starting at February 2020 to June 2020.
Previously I graduated from KULeuven, Belgium in June 2017 with a Bachelor of Science in Informatics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rasterizer</title>
      <link>https://nickelium.github.io/portfolio/rasterizer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 12:32:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nickelium.github.io/portfolio/rasterizer/</guid>
      <description>This is a simple realtime software renderer that emulates the typical graphics pipeline. Therefore it doesn&amp;rsquo;t use the help of any Graphics API such as D3D11/12, OpenGL or Vulkan. The software is built mostly from &amp;lsquo;scratch&amp;rsquo;, written in standard C++98/C++11. To be more precise, the renderer tries to mimick the OpenGL pipeline by providing it&amp;rsquo;s implementation instead of relying on the GPU.
The goal of this project is to learn and uncover what&amp;rsquo;s behind the blackbox of a Graphics API that is often untold (to me at least) and taken as it is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello</title>
      <link>https://nickelium.github.io/post/hello/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 11:23:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nickelium.github.io/post/hello/</guid>
      <description>Hello World ! Welcome to my personal website/portfolio page.
This site serves as a place to show my personal projects and also to share some of my thoughts in the form of an informal blog post.
Most of the content that are about to come will be presumably related to Programming (C/C++, &amp;hellip;) and Rendering (Rasterization, Raytracing, &amp;hellip;) which I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to share.
This is the very first post on this website and is also intended to verify it&amp;rsquo;s full functionality and correctness.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>